REGINE HEIMERS



CONTACT

BARCKHAUSENSTR. 30, 21335 LUENEBURG

 $\searrow \langle$

REGINEHEIMERS@GMAIL.COM

in

WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/REGINEHEIMERS

6

+49 [0] 163 684 87 83

EDUCATION

PH.D. | CONSUMER BEHAVIOR

01.2014 - 02.2019

Georg-August-University Goettingen, Goettingen, Germany

 Foci: quantitative & qualitative marketing research, consumer behavior, digital customer management

• Thesis: Customer Engagement in the German Wine Industry

M.SC. | WINE BUSINESS

09.2010

- 03.2012

ESC Dijon Bourgogne, Dijon, France

Foci: management, marketing, entrepreneurship & wine consumer behavior

• Thesis: Multi-Channel-Retailing in the German Wine Industry

B.SC. | BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

09.2007 -06.2010 University of Mannheim, Mannheim, Germany

- Foci: international management, marketing & sales, finance, accounting & taxation, business informatics
- Thesis: Inheritance and Gift Tax in the Context of Private and Capital Companies
- Semester abroad: National Chengchi University, Taipei, Taiwan with focus on new product development & emerging markets

SKILLS

LANGUAGE

German: native Microsoft Office: very good

English: fluent Statistic programs

French: intermediate SPSS, AMOS, MAXQDA: very good

Chinese: basic Microsoft Dynamics NAV: very good

SAP ERP: basic

PROFILE

I am a wine and spirits geek with excellent communication skills and a passion for data-driven marketing, customer-oriented solutions as well as creative tasks. I love to develop new projects and to proceed from concept to action. With eight years of experience in marketing research and over ten years of experience in wine and spirits, I am looking forward to a position that combines strategic and operative tasks.

EXPERIENCE

DEPUTY MANAGING DIRECTOR

Winery Dr. Heimers, Offstein, Germany

- Responsible for event management & customer care
- · Responsible for a team of up to five people
- Expanded export to Asia
- Extended the sparkling wine product line
- Developed and implemented the "winemaker at your home" events

MARKETING RESEARCH ASSOCIATE

01.2014 -01.2019

05 2013

06.2020

Ludwigshafen University of Business & Society, Ludwigshafen, Germany

- Researched in customer management and digital customer engagement
- Created a loyalty program as an engagement platform
- Generated research funding (six-digit euro amount)
- Managed research projects of business clients:
 - I. Co-developed a wine app for vinocheck uG
 - II. Co-developed a viticulture project / a wine brand as part of Europe's largest river rehabilitation project the Emscher renaturation

CUSTOMER DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

01.2014

Winery Markgraf von Baden GmbH & Co. KG, Salem, Germany

-04.2015

- The position was linked to my Ph.D. project
- Conducted an extensive customer analyses which resulted in the implementation of a wine loyalty program
- Optimized the CRM system (Microsoft Dynamics NAV)
- Conducted competitor analyses

MARKETING RESEARCH ASSOCIATE

07.2012

03.2013

Christian-Albrechts-University Kiel, Kiel, Germany

- Researched in storytelling
- Developed a brand story for the business client Scheibel distillery
- Lectured in cross-cultural marketing

MANAGEMENT TRAINEE

09.2011

02.2012

Remstalkellerei Wine Cooperative, Weinstadt, Germany

CONTROLLING TRAINEE

06.2008 Suedzucker AG, Mannheim, Germany

LOGISTICS TRAINEE

04.2007 -05.2007

08.2008

Blauth Import- und Vertriebsgesellschaften mbH, Linhai, China